Guide to the Franz R. and Kathryn M. Stenzel Research Files on Western American Art
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- James Madison Alden, 1877-1978; Series I; 2.52; (6 boxes)
  - RESEARCH FILES
    - Maps
      - McMurtrie, William B. "Reconnaissance of the Western Coast of the United States [Lower Sheet] San Francisco to San Diego." Engraving, 1853
        "By the Hydrographic Party under the
        command of Lieut. James Alden USN
        Assist."
      - McMurtrie, William B. "Reconnaissance of the Western Coast of the United States. Middle Sheet From San Francisco to Umpquah River." Engraving, 1854
      - McMurtrie, William B. "Reconnaissance of the Western Coast of the United States [Northern Sheet] From Umpquah River to the Boundary." Engraving, 1855
      - U.S. Coast Survey maps of Washington and Oregon. Hydrography by the Party under the Command of Lieut. James Alden U.S.N. Assistant. 11 maps, 1853-54
    - Photographs
      - U.S.S. "Black Hawk." Carte-de-visite photograph, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 81)
        With note on verso "My father was on
        in [blank]" signed S. A. Dorsey
      - Waterman, O. W. "U.S.S. Alden." U.S. Navy calendar for 1933 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Other Papers
      - Genealogical chart of the John Alden family, n.d.
      - Letter to Chamber of Commerce, Olympia Washington, from Eliza L. Wright. Copy, 1935 May 20 (Box 2, Folder 83)
      - List of Alden paintings in the possession of the Adams family which were photographed 11/65, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 84)
      - Notes, correspondence, and photographic postcards from Helen Van Cleave Park relating to Marin County views by Alden, 1973-76, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 85-86)
      - Stenzel's notes on Alden and William B. McMurtrie's maps and sketches (Box 2, Folder 87)
      - "Private Notes of Philip C. Johnson, Jr. On board U.S.S. Active 1855-56," typescript copy, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 88)
        Original is in the University of
        Washington Library
      - Miscellaneous research materials, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 89)
      - Empty envelope labeled "Portrait of Wm. B. McMurtrie", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - WRITINGS
    - Chapter Drafts
      - Early draft, typescript carbon, corrected, with notes by Kathryn Stenzel, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 91-95)
        Originally housed in a notebook
        labeled "Yankee Alden, Artist on
        the Pacific Coast, 1854-1860"
      - Early draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 96-99)
        Includes acknowledgments not present
        in draft above. Originally housed in
        a second notebook labeled "Yankee
        Alden, Artist on the Pacific Coast,
        1854-1860"
      - Later draft, typescript, corrected, with letters and copy photographs, 1973-74, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 100-103)
        labeled "Yankee Alden." Accompanied
        by typescript of paper presented at
        the Western History Conference,
        October 11, 1973
      - Later draft, typescript copy, with editor's annotations, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 104-106)
      - Later draft, typescript photocopy, index corrected (Box 4, Folder 107-109)
        labeled "Meet Limner Alden"
      - Later draft of chapters 1, 2, and 7, typescript photocopy, uncorrected (Box 4, Folder 110)
      - Later draft of chapters 1 and 2, typescript carbon, with editor's annotations (Box 4, Folder 111)
      - Later draft of chapters 1, 2, and 7, typescript photocopy, corrected (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - Other Papers
      - "James Madison Alden, Survey Artist, 1854-1861." Paper presented at Western History Conference at Amon Carter Museum of Western Art, October 11, 1973. Typescript, corrected (Box 5, Folder 113)
      - Grant application for Alden exhibition and book. Copy (Box 5, Folder 114)
      - Copy photographs of Alden artwork arranged according to year of painting, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 115-117)
      - Copy photographs of Alden artwork, with notes and letters, 1973-75, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 118-121)
        Accompanied by notes of illustrations
        used
      - Copy photographs of Alden artwork arranged according to owner, with correspondence and documents related to copying the artwork, 1971-74, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 122-126)
      - Correspondence and documents relating to Alden exhibitions, 1974-75 (Box 5, Folder 127)
        Includes correspondence with the
        Amon Carter Museum of Western Art
      - Press releases, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 128)
      - Invitations to opening reception for James Madison Alden exhibit at Amon Carter Museum of Western Art, [1975] (Box 6, Folder 129)
      - Photographs of James Madison Alden exhibition opening and installation at Amon Carter Museum of Western Art, [1975] (Box 6, Folder 130-131)
      - Amon Carter Museum Publications catalog advertising book, [1976] (Box 6, Folder 132)
      - Recipient list for presentation copies of book. Holograph, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 133)
      - Clippings: book reviews, [1975-76] (Box 6, Folder 134-137)
      - Quotes from book reviews, typescript copy, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 138)
      - Clippings: exhibit announcements and reviews, [1975-76] (Box 6, Folder 139-141)
      - Canceled checks for purchase of Alden watercolors, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 142)
      - Return receipts for Alden artwork mailed by Stenzel, 1974-75 (Box 6, Folder 143)
- James G. Swan, 1870-1979; Series II; 1.05; (3 boxes)
  Series II, James G. Swan, is organized into three
  subseries: Correspondence, Printed Material, and Other
  Papers. Correspondence is organized into James G. Swan
  Correspondence, Franz Stenzel Correspondence, and Other
  Correspondence. Printed Material is organized into
  Pamphlets, Clippings, and Other Printed Material. For
  other research material relating to Swan, see also the
  Artist Information Index, Main Index in Series V, box
  34, folder 611.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - James G. Swan Correspondence
      - Letters to Spencer Fullerton Baird, 1850-1890. Copies from the Smithsonian and Bureau of American Ethnology correspondence files (Box 7, Folder 144-147)
      - Letters to H. H. Bancroft and "Statement of James G. Swan of Port Townsend, Washington Territory written for H. H. Bancroft, Esq." Typed transcripts and holograph notes from material in the Bancroft Library (Box 7, Folder 148)
      - Letters to John Wesley Powell, and Albert P. Niblack in the Archives of the Bureau of American Ethnology, Smithsonian Institution, 1871-1888. Copies (Box 7, Folder 149)
      - Letters to William Winlock Miller and Elwood Evans, 1859-1863 in the William Winlock Miller Collection at the Beinecke Library. Copies, [1963] (Box 7, Folder 150)
      - Letter to Charles E. Mix, Commissioner of Indian Affairs, Washington, 1858 Jan 25. Copy from unidentified institution (Box 7, Folder 151)
    - Franz Stenzel Correspondence
      - Alaska Historical Library and Museum, 1958 Sep 23 (Box 7, Folder 152)
      - "B"-"H" general, 1956-75, n.d (Box 7, Folder 153)
      - Bancroft Library, 1958-71 (Box 7, Folder 154)
        Includes photocopies of letters to
        George Davidson from Swan
      - Bartlett, Elizabeth L., 1958 Dec 7 (Box 7, Folder 155)
      - California Historical Society, 1960, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 156)
      - Dixon, Ruth, 1963-74 (Box 7, Folder 157)
        Stored also in: Oversize, box 57,
        folder 1572
      - Ellis, Margaret F., 1959-64 (Box 7, Folder 158)
        folder 1573
      - Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery, 1958-64 (Box 7, Folder 159)
      - "J"-"S" general, 1958-67, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 160)
      - Library of Congress, 1958 Sep 17 (Box 7, Folder 161)
      - National Archives and Records Service, 1960 Jan 18 (Box 8, Folder 162)
      - Provincial Archives of Victoria, B.C., 1958, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 163)
      - Public Archives of Canada, 1958 Sep 11 (Box 8, Folder 164)
      - Smithsonian Institution. Bureau of American Ethnology, 1963-64 (Box 8, Folder 165)
      - Smithsonian Institution. National Collection of Fine Arts, 1958 Sep 9 (Box 8, Folder 166)
      - Swan, Charles P., 1971-74, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 167)
        Includes photocopy of letter from
        Swan to his wife dated 1850 Dec 1
      - "U" general, 1958-59, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 168)
      - University of Washington Libraries, 1966 Aug-Oct (Box 8, Folder 169)
      - University of Washington Press, 1967 Nov 14 (Box 8, Folder 170)
      - Washington State Historical Society, 1959-60 (Box 8, Folder 171)
      - Yale University Library, 1958, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 172)
    - Other Correspondence
      - Letters to Joseph Henry, Secretary, Smithsonian Institution from George Gibbs. Copies from the Smithsonian Institution, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 173-174)
  - PRINTED MATERIAL
    - Pamphlets
      - Swan, James G. Appendix to William Gouverneur Morris' Report upon the Customs District, Public Service, and Resources of Alaska Territory. Washington: Government Printing Office. Copy from the Bancroft Library, 1879 (Box 8, Folder 175)
      - Allison, Guy. Forgotten Great Man of Washington History James G. Swan. A biographical account. Pamphlet, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 176)
        Two copies. Signed by Guy Allison
        on front cover of one copy
      - A Brief Sketch of The Life of General Hazard Stevens. Boston: Geo. H. Ellis Co., Printers, 1908 (Box 8, Folder 177)
      - Canfield, Thomas H. Northern Pacific Railroad. Partial Report to the Board of Directors, of a Portion of a Reconnoissance made in the Summer of 1869, between Lake Superior and the Pacific Ocean. May 1870 and Wilkeson, Samuel. Notes on Puget Sound. Copy from the Historical Society of Montana Library (Box 8, Folder 178)
      - United States of America Nautical Chart Symbols and Abbreviations, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 179)
      - Pamphlets about James Swan, 1951, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 180)
      - Miscellaneous pamphlets on Oregon and Washington history, 1948-58 (Box 8, Folder 181)
    - Clippings
      - McDonald, Lucile. Articles on James G. Swan and related people in The Seattle Times, 1955-59 (Box 8, Folder 182)
      - Articles on James Swan, 1951-74 (Box 8, Folder 183)
      - Articles about Oregon and Washington history, 1870-1972, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 184)
      - Miscellaneous clippings, 1961-70, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 185)
    - Other Printed Material
      - Letter from James G. Swan regarding his election to the Board of Curators of the Washington State Historical Society October 21, 1891. Printed for the meeting of the Board of Curators of the Washington State Historical Society. Two copies, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 186)
      - Advertisement for Almost Out of the World. Glimpses of Life in Washington Territory from Washington State Historical Society, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 187)
      - Middleton, Eve. Postcards of "Authentic Northwest Indian Tattoo Marks from James G. Swan Papers, 1874." (Box 8, Folder 188)
      - Road maps of Washington State, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 189)
  - OTHER PAPERS
    - Swan genealogical information. Copies and typed transcripts (Box 8, Folder 190)
      Includes two photocopies and typed
      transcripts of letters to Ellen M.
      Swan, dated 1893 and 1897. Material
      in this folder was housed in a
      manila folder labeled "C. P. Swan
      material"
    - Franz Stenzel's notes on Swan, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 191-193)
      folder 1574
    - Franz Stenzel's bibliographical notes on Swan, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 194)
    - Guide to the James G. Swan Diaries at the University of Washington Library. Copy (Box 9, Folder 195)
    - Swan drawings at the Smithsonian Institution. Copy photographs (Box 9, Folder 196)
    - Swan drawings and photograph of Swan and his interpreter, Johnny Kit Elswa. Copy photographs from the Smithsonian Institution Museum of Natural History (Box 9, Folder 197)
    - Swan and man next to a canoe. Copy photographs from unidentified source (Box 9, Folder 198)
    - Portrait of Swan from unidentified source. Copy photograph, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 199)
    - Waktlemuk, or Martha. Native American girl. Copy photographs, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 200)
    - Photographic postcards of a modern map of Bruceport and the Peninsula "the World's Longest Beach" (Box 9, Folder 201)
- E. S. Paxson, 1932-1964; Series III; 0.21; (1 box)
  Series III, E. S. Paxson, is organized into two
  subseries: Research Files and Writings. For other
  research material relating to Paxson, see also the
  21, folders 406-407.
  - RESEARCH FILES
    - Letter from W. L. Creden to R. J. Hale concerning Paxson's painting "Buffalo Hunt", 1954 Mar 2 (Box 10, Folder 202)
    - Women's Club talk given by E. S. Paxson's daughter Feb 6, 1931. Typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 203)
    - Partoll, Albert J., ed. After the Custer Battle, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 204)
      Reprint of a letter written by E.
      S. Godfrey to Paxson
    - "A Portfolio of The Art of E. S. Paxson." Montana Historical Society Press and Montana Magazine of History, Spring 1954 issue (Box 10, Folder 205)
    - Clippings, 1932, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 206)
    - Photograph reproductions of paintings by Paxson, 1949, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 207)
    - Paxson paintings reproduced as advertising and in Butte, Center of Montana Wonderland (Box 10, Folder 208)
  - WRITINGS
    - "E. S. Paxson--Montana Painter." Typescript, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 209)
    - "E. S. Paxson - Montana Painter." Montana Heritage Series no. 14, published by the Montana Historical Society, n.d.
- Cleveland Rockwell, 1957-1975; Series IV; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  Series IV, Cleveland Rockwell is organized into two
  subseries: Research Files and Writings. The Research
  Files are organized into Correspondence, Printed Material
  and Other Papers. Writings are organized into Chapter
  Drafts and Other Papers. For other research material
  relating to Rockwell, see also the Artist Information
  Index, Main Index in Series V, box 34, folder 610.
  - RESEARCH FILES
    - Correspondence
      - "A-C" general, 1958-73 (Box 11, Folder 210)
      - Adams, Earl, 1972 Aug 28 (Box 11, Folder 211)
      - American Watercolor Society, 1971 Nov 21 (Box 11, Folder 212)
      - Archives of American Art, 1971 Oct 24 (Box 11, Folder 213)
      - Baird, Joseph Armstrong, 1972 Jul 9 (Box 11, Folder 214)
      - Bancroft Library, 1971-72 (Box 11, Folder 215)
      - California Academy of Sciences, 1971-72 (Box 11, Folder 216)
      - California Department of Public Health, 1971-72 (Box 11, Folder 217)
      - California Historical Society, 1971-73 (Box 11, Folder 218)
      - Carruthers, Eben, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 219)
      - "D-F" general, 1971-73, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 220)
      - Delehanty, R. D., Mrs., 1971-72 (Box 11, Folder 221)
      - DeWitt, O. K., Mrs., 1965-72 (Box 11, Folder 222)
      - Edward Eberstadt & Sons, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 223)
      - Edwards, David, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 224)
      - "G-K" general, 1971-72, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 225)
      - Glenbow-Alberta Institute, 1972, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 226)
      - Graves, Eleanor; Graves, Lloyd, 1957-71 (Box 11, Folder 227)
      - Harrison, Michael, 1972-73 (Box 11, Folder 228)
      - Henry E. Huntington Library, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 229)
      - John Howell Books, 1972 Aug 28 (Box 11, Folder 230)
      - Kennedy Galleries, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 231)
      - Kent Company, 1971 Nov (Box 11, Folder 232)
      - Library of Congress, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 233)
      - "M" general, 1971-72 (Box 11, Folder 234)
      - Mackenzie, Marian, 1964-72 (Box 11, Folder 235)
      - McCall, Thomas, 1972 Aug 22 (Box 11, Folder 236)
      - Montana State Board of Health, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 237)
      - Montgomery, Richard, 1971-72 (Box 11, Folder 238)
      - National Archives and Records Service, 1962-73 (Box 11, Folder 239)
      - New Haven Registrar of Vital Statistics, 1971-72 (Box 11, Folder 240)
      - New-York Historical Society, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 241)
      - New York University Libraries, 1971-72 (Box 11, Folder 242)
      - "O-R" general, 1971-72 (Box 11, Folder 243)
      - Oakland Art Museum, 1972 Jan 21 (Box 11, Folder 244)
      - Oregon Historical Society, 1971-72, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 245)
      - Oregon State Board of Health, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 246)
      - Price, Vincent, 1973 Mar 9 (Box 11, Folder 247)
      - Renssalaer Polytechnic Institute, 1971-72 (Box 11, Folder 248)
      - Rockwell Gallery of Western Art, 1971-72 (Box 11, Folder 249)
      - "S" general, 1971-73 (Box 11, Folder 250)
      - San Francisco National Cemetery, 1971-72 (Box 11, Folder 251)
      - Siebert, Frank T., 1972 (Box 11, Folder 252)
      - Smithsonian Institution, 1971-72 (Box 11, Folder 253)
      - Steen, Harold; Steen, Judith, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 254)
      - Stossell, Lee (Box 11, Folder 255)
      - Tinney, Christine, 1971-72 (Box 11, Folder 256)
      - U.S. Department of Commerce Coast and Geodetic Survey, 1963-64 (Box 11, Folder 257)
      - Vose Galleries, 1972 Mar 10 (Box 11, Folder 258)
      - Washington State Historical Society, 1972 Jan 18 (Box 11, Folder 259)
      - Western Reserve Historical Society, 1971-72 (Box 11, Folder 260)
      - Wolcott, John, 1973, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 261)
      - Yale University Library, 1971-72 (Box 11, Folder 262)
      - Yost, Karl, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 263)
    - Printed Material
      - Rockwell, Cleveland. "The Grand Coulee," The Pacific Monthly, vol. II, no. 3, July 1899. Copy (Box 11, Folder 264)
      - Rockwell, Cleveland. "A Mediaeval Medallion," The Pacific Monthly, vol. V, no. 6, May 1901. Copy (Box 11, Folder 265)
    - Other Papers
      - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 266)
  - WRITINGS
    - Chapter Drafts
      - Acknowledgments. Typescript, corrected, with letters from people and institutions to be acknowledged, and research notes, 1970-72, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 267)
      - Chapter I. Typescript, corrected, with research material, 1971, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 268)
      - Chapter II. Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 269)
      - Chapter III. Typescript, corrected, with research material, 1971, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 270)
      - Chapter IV. Typescript, corrected, with research material, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 271)
      - Chapter V and Art. Typescript, corrected, with research material, 1971-72, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 272)
      - Chronology, Paintings, and Bibliography. Typescript, corrected, with research material, 1972, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 273)
    - Other Papers
      - Copy photographs of Rockwell artwork, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 274)
      - Copies of illustrations in Rockwell book, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 275)
      - Invitations to Rockwell opening and Stenzel autograph party, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 276)
      - Photographs of Rockwell book autograph party, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 277)
      - Catalogs advertising book, 1973-75 (Box 12, Folder 278)
      - Recipient list for presentation copies of book. Holograph, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 279)
      - Clippings: book reviews, 1972-73 (Box 12, Folder 280)
      - Clippings: Rockwell exhibition, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 281)
      - Receipts for expenses incurred while researching and writing book, 1971-72 (Box 12, Folder 282)
      - Certificate of Commendation from The American Association for State and Local History. Photographic reproduction (Box 12, Folder 283)
- Research Files for an Unpublished Book on Western Art, 1859-1997; Series V; 9.66; (23 boxes)
  Series V, Research Files for an Unpublished Book on Western Art are Franz Stenzel's working files for
  a book with the projected title, Art of the Oregon Country, which was never published. The series is
  organized into two subseries: Research Files and Writings.
  Research Files are arranged by Artist Information Indexes
  (subdivided by Main File, Oregon Sculpture File, Alberta
  File, British Columbia File and "Not Northwest" File) and
  Other Subject Files.
  - RESEARCH FILES
    - Artist Information Index
      - Main File
        - Achey - Adams, 1952-65, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 284)
          Files for:
          Achey, Mary E.
          Adams, Cassilly
          Adams, Charles Partridge
        - Agate, Alfred, 1964-90, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 285)
        - Akin - Alden, 1961-71, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 286)
          Akin, Louis B.
          Albright, Theodore
          Alden, James Madison
        - Aldrich - Amstrong, 1965-74, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 287)
          Aldrich, L. W.
          Alexander, John White
          Allen, Gregory Seymour
          Amann, C. R.
          Anderson, Abraham Archibald
          Anderson, F. E. James
          Armstrong, William Walton
        - Back - Baker, 1960-63, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 288)
          Back, Joe
          Bacon, Irving R.
          Baker, George Holbrook
        - Barchus, Eliza, 1905-74, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 289)
          Includes Barchus' Art Souvenir,
          printed for the Lewis and Clark
          Exposition, 1905, and a postcard
          reproduction of a painting of Mt.
          Rainier, copyrighted 1905
        - Barnes - Bayless, 1963-66, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 290)
          Barnes, Albert Henry
          Barrows, William A.
          Bartlett, Dana
          Baumgras, Peter
          Bayless, J. A.
        - Beard - Beil, 1962-67, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 291)
          Beard, Daniel Carter
          Beard, James Carter
          Beecher, Harriet Foster
          Beek, Alice D. Engley
          Beek, Raphael
          Beil, Charles A.
          Stored also in: Oversize, box 58,
          folder 1599
        - Bell - Biberstein, 1929-74, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 292)
          Bell, Sidney
          Best, Arthur William
          Best, Henry Cassie
          Biberstein, Franz
          Includes annotated exhibition
          catalog and photographs of Arthur
          William Best and Yosemite Nature Notes, Vol. XXIV, No. 3, March
          1945 with article on Henry Cassie
          Best
        - Bierstadt, Albert, 1872-1971, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 293)
        - Bigelow - Blakelock, 1962-68, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 294)
          Bigelow, Constance
          Biles, James Norman
          Black, Mollie E.
          Blakelock, Ralph Albert
          folder 1600
        - Bloodgood - Blumenschein, 1903-74, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 295)
          Bloodgood, Morris Seymour
          Bloodgood, Robert Fanshawe
          Bloomer, Hiram Reynolds
          Blumenschein, Ernest Leonard
          Includes an article in Century magazine with illustrations by
          Blumenschein
        - Bodmer, Karl, 1963-68, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 296)
        - Bohlman - Borein, 1962-68, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 297)
          Bohlman, Herman T.
          Boone, Elmer
          Borein, Edward
        - Borg, Carl Oscar, 1930-68, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 298)
          Includes letter to "Old Timer"
          (otherwise unidentified) from
          Borg dated 1930 Dec 20
        - Borglum, Gutzon, 1963-69, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 299)
          Includes photographs of Borglum's
          artwork and a photographic portrait
          of Borglum
          folder 1601
        - Borglum, Solon, 1963-67, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 300)
          folder 1602
        - Bowman - Branson, 1963-65, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 301)
          Bowman, Daniel Webster
          Bradford, William
          Bradley, Elizabeth
          Bransom, Paul
          Branson, Fannie
        - Brenner, Carl Christian - Brewer, Henry Joseph, 1947-64, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 302)
        - Brewerton, George Douglas, 1960-69, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 303)
          folder 1575
        - Britt - Brown, Grafton, 1961-74, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 304)
          Britt, Peter
          Brookman, Herman
          Brown, Grafton Tyler
        - Brown, J. F. - Browne, Belmore, 1962-64, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 305)
          Brown, J. F.
          Brown, Robert
          Browne, Belmore
        - Browne, J. Ross - Brownell, Franklin, 1962-65, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 306)
        - Brush - Bull, 1885-1965, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 307)
          Brush, George DeForest
          Bryce, Robert Clyde
          Byrde, James